Preliminary Guide to the Patricia Miller Papers, 1967-1972
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Patricia Miller papers 1967-1972
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Miller, Patricia.
0.6 linear feet Extent: 500 Items
Patricia Miller is an attorney, abortion rights activist, and the author of The Worst of Times: Illegal Abortion--Survivors, Practitioners, Coroners, Cops, and Children of Women Who Died Talk About its Horrors. Collection includes Miller's personal correspondence, materials and background information from the Pennsylvania Abortion Law Commission, and general pro and con abortion materials from Pennsylvania and Colorado.
millerpatricia
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Patricia Miller Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2009.
Biographical Note
Patricia Miller is an attorney, a long-time abortion rights activist, and the author of The Worst of Times: Illegal Abortion--Survivors, Practitioners, Coroners, Cops, and Children of Women Who Died Talk About its Horrors (1993), an oral history compilation.
Collection Overview
Collection includes Miller's personal correspondence, materials and background information from the Pennsylvania Abortion Law Commission, and general abortion materials from rights activists and opponents in Pennsylvania and Colorado.
Collection Arrangement
This collection has not been fully processed, and as such, materials have not been refoldered beyond what is needed for preservation purposes. Furthermore, most labels are directly transcribed from the donor's description of the material.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Miller, Patricia G., 1933-; Abortion -- Pennsylvania; Abortion -- Colorado; Pennsylvania -- Abortion Law Commission
Contents of Collection
- Accession (2009-0161), 1967-1972, (1 box)
  Accession (2009-0161) (500 items; 0.6 lin. ft.; dated 1967-1971) includes Miller's personal correspondence, materials and background information from the Pennsylvania Abortion Law Commission, and general abortion materials from rights activists and opponents in Pennsylvania and Colorado.
  - Abortion pro/con Pennsylvania: religious views, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - Pennsylvania: recommended legislation
  - Pennsylvania Abortion Law Commission (PALC): Legal Committee, 1972
  - Pennsylvania Abortion Law Commission (PALC): Report of the Socio-Economic Committee, 1971
  - Pennsylvania Abortion Law Commission (PALC): Majority Report draft
  - Pennsylvania Abortion Law Commission (PALC): Loose materials
  - Personal correspondence, 1972
  - Pro and Anti Organizations: Material from abortion opponents, 1972
  - Colorado materials
  - Colorado and other states news clippings, 1967